29. Say hello to our new mechanical friends.
For years we've been hearing it. The robots are coming. The robots are coming.
Well, the long wait is finally over. The robots are no longer coming. They're already here.
The robotics industry has changed economies and lifestyles around the world.
One area in which these changes are particularly obvious is manufacturing.
Industrial robots, those robot arms that assemble things in factories, are becoming increasingly capable.
Nowadays, these robots can assemble large items like cars with very little input from human workers.
They can also work 24 hours a day without ever making a mistake.
It's no wonder that factory workers around the world are losing their jobs to robots.
Of course, that's not what comes to mind when most of us think of robots.
We imagine personal, human-like machines that can cook our food and do our laundry for us.
Fortunately, they're here as well.
Tech companies are fighting tooth and nail to achieve the first big success in personal robotics.
Japan's Sharp Electronics is betting on simpler, more affordable robots.
For this reason, it has launched RoboHon, a cute little robot that functions similarly to a smartphone.
RoboHon can understand simple voice commands.
It also knows some pretty sweet dance moves, which it shows off whenever it receives a phone call.
Other companies are targeting the high-end market with technologically advanced personal robots.
Two examples are Honda's Asimo and SoftBank's Pepper.
Asimo can run, jump, and climb stairs just like a human being.
It also has sensitive hands that can perform delicate tasks like pouring a cup of coffee.
Pepper, on the other hand, can sense and respond to human emotions.
This could come in handy when dealing with people who have lost their livelihoods to robots.